Cameron Bibb

PROFILE

I am a software engineer with experience in JavaScript, TypeScript, Go, Ruby, PostgreSQL, and React. I am a co-creator of Willow, an open-source framework for creating change data capture pipelines. I use skills gained in seminary and honed in my previous career to logically and methodically break down complex problems and write clear, maintainable code.

EXPERIENCE

Creator, Software Engineer, Willow

2024 - present

Willow (willow-cdc.github.io ☑) is an open-source framework for creating change data capture pipelines. It reflects database changes to a cache in near real-time.

- Developed framework to simplify change data capture pipeline creation from 9 steps to 4 steps
- Architected and implemented **RESTful API** facilitating pipeline creation and teardown (**Node.js, Express**)
- Designed and constructed a custom Kafka connector to transform events from Kafka and send them to a cache (Node.js, KafkaJS, Redis)
- Built user-friendly UI to streamline pipeline management (React, Material UI)
- Resolved Debezium configuration issues preventing multiple pipelines from connecting to the same database (PostgreSQL, Debezium)
- Ensured Willow functions when provided a minimum privileged database user, avoiding the need to provide Willow with superuser privileges
- Collaborated remotely with an international team of four engineers using daily stand-ups and pair programming (Git, GitHub, Slack)
- Authored comprehensive technical case study (willow-cdc.github.io/case-study <a href="mailto:z).

Software Engineer, Self-Employed / Personal Projects

2021 - 2024

Developed freelance and open-source applications including:

- Requests A RequestBin clone for testing webhooks (React, PM2, DigitalOcean, Nginx, MongoDB)
- BackLog Update A web app for organizing a videogame backlog (Ruby, Sinatra, PostgreSQL, HTML/CSS)

Media and Design, First United Methodist Church, Lexington, KY

2021 - 2023

- Maintained and edited website across three church communities (HTML/CSS, WordPress)
- Installed and operated technical equipment for A/V and live streaming

SKILLS

Back End

Node.js/Express, Ruby, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Redis, SQL, RESTful APIs, Go, TypeScript

Front End

JavaScript, React, MaterialUI, HTML/CSS, jQuery, Handlebars.js, Axios, TailwindCSS

Cloud

AWS, DigitalOcean, Heroku

Technologies

Git/Github, Docker, Apache Kafka, Linux, Bash, WebHooks

EDUCATION

Launch School 2021 - 2024

Multi-year, mastery-based software engineering curriculum. Read more at launchschool.com/employers 🗵

2010 – 2016 | Wilmore, KY **Asbury Theological Seminary, M.Div.**

2010 – 2016 | Wilmore, KY **Asbury Theological Seminary,** M.A., Theological Studies

East Carolina University, B.A., Philosophy 2003 - 2008 | Greenville, NC